(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E14 -= First.Blood =- Subripped by zerox
珍妮，不是说不想去.
Look, Jennifer, it's not that I don't want to go with you Saturday...
我还有别的事情呢
it's just that I've got this prior commitment.
我要捐献肾脏
I'm donating a kidney.
不过别告诉任何人
Look, but don't tell anybody.
不然大家抢着要
Well, 'cause then everybody'll want one.
若是捐不成我在通知你
Look, if the deal falls through, I'll let you know.
好吧，再见
Okay, all right, bye-bye.
你拒绝了跟珍妮约会？
You turned down a date with Jennifer Miller?
“大波波”珍妮？
Jennifer "Wonder Buns" Miller?
我看女人并不注重外表
Hey, my attraction to women is not entirely based on physical beauty.
对，她们还得愚蠢
Yeah, they gotta be stupid, too.
麦克，你不是很喜欢珍妮的吗？
Mike, I thought you liked Jennifer.
是的，但是她要我做一些 一万年也不会做的事
Yeah, but she wants me to do something I'd never do in a million years.
什么？看书？
What? Read a book?
不，更糟糕，她让我参加姐姐的婚礼
No, worse, she wants me to go to her sister's wedding...
还要跳舞
and go ballroom dancing.
老天爷真是瞎了 怎么能如此对孩子们
As God is our witness, they can't make our baby do this.
你们尽管取笑.
Okay, fine, fine. You guys go ahead and laugh...
我麦克.西弗绝对不想 在200人面前出洋相
but Michael Seaver is not gonna make a fool of himself in front of 200 people.
你的洋相已经不少了
Yeah, you're used to a much bigger crowd.
麦克，跳舞也有好处.
Mike, there are advantages to ballroom dancing.
可以亲密接触你的舞伴
You know, you actually get to touch your partner...
手牵手，脸贴脸
hand to hand, cheek to cheek...
还有什么什么贴着什么什么
everything else to everything else.
杰森!
Oh, Jason!
如果你有魅力，如果你懂诀窍.
And if you're a real cool guy, and you learn all the moves, Mike...
使用魅力和诀窍.
well, the right guy and the right moves...
绝对能让女人.
can absolutely make the right woman...
融化
melt.
还有些诀窍要在房间里施展
There are more moves, but they require a motel room.
不，注意观察
Not so. Observe.
法国式
The French dip.
还有些诀窍，但是要好吃的东西
There are more moves, but they require gravy.
珍妮，是我，捐不成了
Yeah, Jennifer, Mike. Look, the deal fell through.
不知道，看来肾脏已经供过于求了
I don't know. Apparently, there's a real glut on the world kidney market.
是的，我们去参加婚礼
Yeah, so we're on for the wedding.
是的，我会带好吃的来
Yeah, and I'll bring the gravy.
先别管，那是舞蹈术语
Never mind, it's a dancing term.
好的，再见
Yeah, okay, bye-bye.
好极了
All right, Mike.
对，我一定要让她融化
All right, Dad. You know, I'm gonna make her melt.
我还没见过融化了的“大波波”呢
I have never seen "Wonder Buns" melt before.
且慢，我还不会跳舞呢
Wait a minute. I don't even know how to dance.
没关系，过来试试看
That's all right, no problem. Come on over here and give it a try.
不是我，跟你妈妈试
Not with me, with your mother.
你需要.
What you try to do is you try to...
-滑步，2，3 -滑步
- glide, two, three. - Glide.
滑步
Glide.
够了!我受够了
That's it! I've had it.
是可忍，孰不可忍!
A man can only take so much.
出问题了？
Something wrong, Ben?
教练的傻儿子罗尼
The new coach and his stupid son, Rodney.
他今天三次用球棍把我绊倒
The kid tripped me three times today with his stick.
下次要给他一点眼色瞧瞧
Next practice, that kid is gonna be sucking the puck.
本，不要说这种话
Now, I don't want to hear that, Ben.
和队员之间有矛盾.
If you have a problem with one of your teammates...
大家是不能解决问题的
fighting is not the answer.
本，你在干什么？
Ben, what are you doing?
锻炼
Pumping milk.
施瓦辛格也是这么过来的
Hey, it worked for Schwarzenegger.
And one. And two. And three.
1，2，3
等等，教练的儿子绊倒你了？
Now wait a minute. Did you try telling the coach that Rodney tripped you?
教练全都看见了
The coach saw the whole thing.
你是说.
Now come on. You mean to tell me...
教练教唆罗尼来阴的？
that the coach actually told Rodney to play dirty?
他让所有队员都来阴的 他讨厌我
He tells all the kids to play dirty. That's why he hates me.
因为众所周知，我是队里的尖子
It's common knowledge, I'm a finesse player.
本，够了
Well, that's it, Ben.
我一直认为冰球太暴力了
I was afraid this hockey thing was going to be too rough.
杰森，这次就离开球队吧
Jason, I think he should quit the team.
不，麦姬 因为兴教练不和而离开球队.
No, Maggie, that's not fair to Ben.
这对本来说不公平
Just because the coach is out of line, you can't make him quit.
下次练习.
I'll go down to the next practice...
我去找教练谈谈
I'll meet the guy, and we'll talk it all over...
你说好不好
if that's okay with you, Ben.
好的，谢谢爸爸
Yeah, thanks, Dad.
你分散教练的注意力.
And while you keep the coach busy talking...
我趁机去踩罗尼的脸
I'll go and skate over Rodney's face.
小女孩们，这是冰球，不是跳舞
Come on, girls, this is hockey, not a square dance.
要大胆地身体接触
I want to see some contact out there.
记住，穿上冰鞋不等于禁止踢人
Remember, just 'cause you're wearing skates doesn't mean you can't kick.
懂吗？
All right?
你好，我叫杰森.西弗
Hello. Hi, I'm Jason Seaver.
我是布克顿教练，你好
Coach Brockton. How are you?
那边7号是我儿子本
That's my boy, Ben, out there, number seven.
他应该增加40磅
Yeah, he could use another 40 pounds.
没问题，我给他打激素吧
Well, no problem. I'll get him started on steroids right away.
很好，家长肯合作就最好了
Good, I like to see the parents get involved.
凯里!
Kelly!
凯里，要懂得传球，不然要!
Kelly, you should've passed off. That's gonna cost you.
对，罚他们留下来跑圈就对了
Sure, make him skate a few extra laps after practice, huh?
教练，有5块散钱吗？
Do you have change for $5, Coach?
还找钱？
What are you talking about, change?
球没交给无人防守的队员 这要罚款5块，去跑一圈
You missed the open man. That is $5. Take a lap.
你对孩子们罚款了？
You're fining these kids?
他不是初犯了
Hey, that is not a first-time offender.
要是有死刑那多好
Too bad they outlawed the death penalty.
是啊
Yeah.
开米罗，你这叫防守？
Carmello, you call that a check?
我老婆在蜜月时打我都比你狠
My wife hit harder on our honeymoon.
你老婆是葛瑞兹基吗？ [著名冰球运动员]
Who'd you marry, Wayne Gretzky?
你敢说我是同性恋？
You calling me a homosexual?
不，我是说你的执教方法太激进了
No, but I do think your coaching methods are a little offensive.
我的队伍所向无敌
Hey, I never had a losing season, buddy.
那恭喜你了
Well, congratulations, buddy...
但孩子们需要在娱乐中.
but I think what's important for these kids is they learn something...
学到东西
they have a little fun.
而不是为了胜利不顾一切
Not win, win, win, at all costs.
越战就是这么输的
That's how we lost Vietnam.
西弗，你是个孬种
You're a wimp, Seaver.
是吗，那你呢？
Oh, really? Well, you know what you are?
什么？
Yeah?
你把孩子们当作出气袋
You're taking a lot of sublimated anger and you're displacing it on these kids.
你他妈的就像心理医生
You sound like you've been to one of them wussy shrinks.
我就是他妈的心理医生
I am one of them wussy shrinks.
我是个精神病医师
I mean, I'm a psychiatrist.
只是你心胸狭隘，自以为是.
Just because you're a little self-absorbed and narrow-minded...
谁自以为是了？
Hey, who are you calling self-absorbent?
你最好收回你的话!
You better be ready to back that up, pal!
别动手动脚的
Keep your hands off me. Okay?
爸爸，教训他
Hit him, Dad.
-本，成年人.. -成你的头
- Ben, that's not the way mature people... - Mature nothing.
-滑步，2，3，好 -滑步，2，3
- Glide, two, three. Right. - Glide, two, three.
-滑步，2，3，滑步，2，3 -滑步，2，3，滑步，2，3
- Glide, two, three. Glide, two, three. - Glide, two, three. Glide, two, three.
麦克，半小时内第5次踩到了
Mike, that's the fifth time in the last half hour.
我进步不少了
Hey, I'm getting better.
很好，今晚到此为止
Good, then let's call it a night.
我还要写文章
I've got an article to finish.
妈妈，明晚就要举行婚礼了 我需要练习
Come on, Mom. The wedding's tomorrow night. I need to practice.
亲爱的，你跳得很好了
Honey, you're doing fine.
而且，我还要换脚上的绷带
Besides, I've gotta change the bandages on my feet.
拜托，连皮都没有破
Come on, I barely broke the skin.
我常常在想.
You know, I often wonder, what's more beautiful?
是繁星夜空漂亮.
The glimmering stars on a clear night...
还是这张脸漂亮？
or this face?
算了吧，我不会和你跳舞的
Forget it. I'm not dancing with you.
跳吧，凯罗，我不会踩你
Come on, Carol. I'm not gonna step on your feet.
你把妈的脚都踩扁了
You stepped all over Mom's.
凯罗，妈妈的脚实在太大了
Carol, the woman has huge feet...
咱私下说好了，妈妈不懂跳舞
and just between you and me, Mom can't dance.
你真是个饭桶
You're such a jerk.
说得对
You're right. I am.
我真的是个饭桶
No, no, really, I am...
所以上天才眷顾我
and that's why I'm so incredibly fortunate...
给了我一位姐姐
to have a sister who's not just a sister...
她是一位仙女
but, well, a saint.
所以我应该叫你.
That's why I think I'll call you...
仙女姐姐
Saint Sister Carol, no Sister Saint Carol.
或者说仙女凯罗，你真的.
No, I got it, Carol Saint Sister, because, after all, Carol, you are...
好了，好了，我宁愿、断脚也不听这些
All right, all right. I'd rather lose a foot than listen to this.
好了吗？
Okay, ready?
滑步，2，3
And glide, two, three.
滑步，2，3，滑步，2，3
Glide, two, three. Glide, two, three...
真好玩
Hey, this is sort of neat.
凯罗，干嘛？
Whoa, Carol, what are you doing?
跳舞
Dancing.
这不是自由舞蹈，这是舞会
Carol, this is not interpretive dancing. This is ballroom dancing.
男人负责带领.
The man is supposed to lead.
女人不动就行了
The woman is supposed to be limp, okay?
息随尊便
Whatever you say.
好吧，再来，滑步，2，3，滑步.
Okay, try it again. And glide, two, three. Glide...
拜托，也不用像死人一样
Come on, Carol, this isn't limp. It's dead.
跟上就行了
Just following your lead.
再来，滑步，2，3，滑步
Okay, let's try it again. Glide, two, three. Glide...
麦克，大有进步了
Hey, Mike, you're doing better.
滑步，2，3.
Glide, two, three...
凯罗，今天到此为止吧
Well, I think that'll be it for today, Carol.
本，怎样了？
Ben, how did it go?
真是太难以相信了
It was unbelievable!
亲爱的，我回家了
Hi, honey. I'm home.
杰森，怎么了？
Jason, what happened?
可以说我和布克顿教练.
Well, I guess you could say Coach Brockton and I had...
进行了一次有意义的思想交流
a brief, but meaningful, exchange of ideas.
还有拳头交流，爸爸打得痛快
And fists! Dad whooped him good!
爸爸，好样的
All right, Dad.
杰森，你跟教练打起来了？
Jason, you mean you actually got in a fight with the coach?
麦姬，是他打我
Well, he took a swing at me, Maggie.
我只是自卫
I had to defend myself.
我去弄点冰块给你敷眼睛
Well, I better get some ice for that eye.
麦克，你看这场面，拳来拳往
Mike, you should have seen it. Pow! Bang! Boom!
布克顿连还手的机会都没有!
Brockton never had a chance!
欢迎来到擂台旁边“猛兽西弗”这里.
And we're here at ringside with Jason "the Animal" Seaver...
还有他的经纪人.
and along with us at ringside is the Animal's manager...
“禽兽”西弗
Benjamin "Bugsy" Seaver.
“禽兽” 今天是如何让拳王热血沸腾的？
Tell us, Bugsy, how did you get the champ's blood boiling for today's bout?
我把哥哥的成绩单让他看了
I showed him his oldest son's report card.
“猛兽”，下一个目标是？
Well, Animal, what's next?
我要击倒霍姆斯.
Well, I want Holmes...
接着是诺顿，接着是克雷顿
and then I want Norton, and then I want Kramden.
接着退隐山林，成为全职心理医生
And then I'm going to retire to pursue psychiatry, full-time.
你这样会让孩子们认为打架是好事
Jason, you're going to make the kids think fighting is a good thing.
说得对，我跟他们说说
You're right. I'll talk to them.
孩子们，我今天的所作所为当受责备
Boys, what I did today was reprehensible.
暴力不是解决问题的方法
Fighting is not the best way to solve your problems.
这点要说清楚
I want that to be clear.
谢谢
Thank you.
麦姬，我不想再为昨天的事.
Maggie, I just don't think I should have to spend another...
花时间去找借口了
24 hours making excuses for what happened yesterday.
因为根本找不到借口
You can't, because there is no excuse.
就像野蛮人一样打架 事后像孩子一样得意
You fought like a barbarian, and then you gloated like a child.
你是个野蛮的孩子
You're a baby-barbarian.
就这么一次意外.
I see, so you're saying by that one incident...
难道就让孩子变成兰波不成？
I'm turning our son into another Rambo.
我回家了
Hi, honey. I'm home.
天哪
Oh, my God.
坐下来，发生什么事了？
Come on, Ben. Sit down. Tell us exactly what happened.
我当时在饭堂.
Right. I was sitting in the cafeteria...
正在吃牛排，还有土豆.
eating my Salisbury steak, mashed potatoes...
还有一种椰菜还是草皮什么的
and something that looked like either broccoli or AstroTurf.
本，打架的事
Ben, the fight.
接着罗尼.布克顿走过来.
Yeah, that's when Rodney Brockton walked over...
把我揪了起来
and pulled me out of my chair.
罗尼.布克顿
Rodney Brockton.
对，我就说“罗尼..”
Yeah. I said, "Rodney, I don't know what makes me sicker...
“你比这顿饭更恶心”
"you or this lunch."
然后我就像“猛兽”杰森一样
Then I did what Jason "the Animal" Seaver would have done.
给他一记拳头
I gave him a knuckle sandwich.
“猛兽”，这下快乐了吗？
Well, Animal, are you proud of yourself?
我并没有快乐
No, Maggie. I'm not proud.
本，罗尼没事吧？
Ben, is Rodney okay?
没事，芬克小姐拉开我们了
Yeah, Miss Finkle came and broke it up...
但是明天中午我们要决斗
but tomorrow at high noon, we meet under the monkey bars...
只有一个人能活下来读4年级
and only one of us makes it to the fourth grade.
太过分了
Well, I've had enough of this.
我要亲自和布克顿谈谈
I'm going down to talk to Brockton myself.
麦姬，事情因我而起
No. No, Maggie. I started this whole thing...
我要让本看看真正的男人 是如何斗争的
so I guess it's time that I showed Ben how a real man fights his battles.
好极了，爸爸!
All right, Dad!
来吧
Come on, Ben.
假定你们在角落，裁判没看到
Now let's say you're mixing it up in the corner. The ref isn't looking.
你们会怎样？
What do you do?
-罗尼，示范 -好的，爸爸
- Rodney, demonstrate. - Okay, Dad.
好极了，比赛时，记得再补上一拳
Perfect. Now in a game, you make sure you follow that up with a punch.
教练，这是犯法的
Excuse me, Coach, but isn't this illegal?
这是冰球场，要合法就去法庭
This is hockey, kid. You want legal, go to law school.
-去跑一圈 -是，教练
- Take a lap. - Yes, sir.
谁来动手？
Okay, so who makes the first move?
我来，你跟着我
I do, you just follow my lead.
好的
Gotcha.
爸爸，看谁来了
Dad, look who's here.
西弗，有何贵干？ 你儿子被球队开除了
What are you doing here, Seaver? Your kid was cut from the team.
教练，我要跟你谈谈
Well, Coach, I'd like to talk to you.
当天说了些侮辱你的话
I know I said some pretty insulting things the other day...
今天我还有一些话要说
and, today, there's something else I'd like to say.
我建议说“你去死吧，胆小鬼!”
Might I suggest, "Drop dead, chicken lips"?
本，让我来
Ben, let me handle this.
布克顿先生，对不起 我是来道歉的
Mr. Brockton, I'm sorry. I came to apologize.
没门，你应该报复
No way, Seaver. I owe you one.
来吧
Come on.
我不是来打架的
Look, I didn't come here to fight.
我不是故意要冒犯你的
I didn't mean to say or do anything to offend you.
你说我老婆是“葛瑞兹基”!
You said I was married to Wayne Gretzky!
这口气我咽不下去
Now I'm not gonna take that, Seaver.
我不是真的说你老婆是“葛瑞兹基”
Look, I didn't mean to say, seriously, that you were married to Wayne Gretzky.
你说我们是罪人？
So you're saying we lived in sin?
我没有含沙射影什么.
I didn't mean to imply that you had any relationship whatsoever...
这么说“葛瑞兹基”也轮不到我娶了吗？
I get it. So now Wayne is too good for me, huh?
我不是说..若你非得如此.
No, I'm not talking... Look, if you're just...
找借口打架.
If you just want another excuse to fight...
我打架不需要找借口，来吧
I don't need any excuses. Come on.
你爸爸怎么不卷起袖子？
How come your dad isn't rolling up his sleeves?
他要是发力，亲衣会被震碎
Once he starts flexing those muscles, his shirt pops off by itself.
咱再打一场
It's rematch time, Seaver.
你要我先动手吗？不客气了
Now you want me to start it, I'll start it.
好吧，要打就打吧 我不是担心我自己
Okay, you want to hit me, go ahead. Fine, hit me. I'm not worried about me.
也没有害怕你，我是担心这些孩子
I'm not worried about you. It's these kids.
要是让孩子们以为暴力能解决问题.
If we can't teach our children that fighting is not the answer, then we have failed...
那我们就愧为父母了
as parents and as human beings.
你可以打我，也可以讲和
So you can hit me, or you can shake my hand.
你自己选吧
Choice is yours.
西弗.
Seaver...
爸爸，教训他!
Now, belt him, Dad!
来吧，孬种，让孩子们见识一下
Yeah, that's right, wuss. Come on, show the kid what you're really made out of.
本，咱回家吧
Come on, Ben. We're going home.
什么？
What?
麦克，抓紧一点.
Hey, Mike, you better get a move on.
珍妮10分钟后就到了
Jennifer's going to be here in 10 minutes.
天哪，忘记淋浴了
Oh, my God. I still have to shower...
还要刮胡子
and shave.
一个月刮一次就行了
Gee, it's another month already?
滑步，2，3，滑步，2，3.
And glide, two, three. Glide, two, three. Glide, two, three. Glide, two, three.
天哪，我长豆豆了
Oh, my God. I've got a zit.
真是苍天有眼
There is a God.
本，你好
Hi, Ben.
我要喝酒
I need a drink.
杰森，怎么了？
Jason, what happened?
布克顿说我是孬种
Well, Coach Brockton called me a wimp...
然后朝我肚子狠狠一拳
and then he punched me as hard as he could in the stomach.
但下面要面对的才是最糟糕的
Now comes the rough part of the evening.
本，喝牛奶解决不了问题
Ben, Ben, milk is not the answer.
没想到你今天这么窝囊
I can't believe you chickened out today.
住嘴，孩子说这话要打屁股的
Now hold on right there. A lot of kids would get spanked for that.
打我吧
Sure, hit me.
好
Okay.
我只是想告诉你道理
Hey, I was just trying to make a point.
你认为我当时应该打布克顿？
Yeah, so you think I should have fought with Coach Brockton today, huh?
他羞辱你了
He slugged you, Dad.
他打我所以我要回敬他？
Yeah, and because he slugged me, I guess I should've slugged him right back?
无可否认，这也是符合逻辑的
You gotta admit, there's a certain logic to it.
本，还记得这件事的起因吗？
Ben, do you remember how this whole thing got started?
罗尼绊倒我
Rodney tripped me.
罗尼绊倒你，所以我去跟教练谈判
Rodney tripped you, and that's why I went down to talk to the coach...
接着我和他打起来
and we ended up punching each other up.
这样问题解决了吗？
Now did that solve anything?
不，但是痛快
No, but it was fun to watch.
对，因为我和教练打架
Yeah, and because I fought with the coach...
第二天你和罗尼又打了
the very next day, you and Rodney slug it out.
解决问题了吗？
Did that solve anything?
没有，所以我们今天又去了一趟
No, that's why we went down there today.
对，若是我还手.
Okay, so suppose I had punched him back...
能解决问题吗？
would that have solved anything?
能，若你打断他的双手双脚.
Yeah, because he would have had two broken arms, two broken legs...
打肿他的脸，他就当不了教练了
a fat lip, and he wouldn't be coaching anymore.
对，当不成教练了
No, he wouldn't be coaching anymore...
但他会坐上电动轮椅.
but he'd go out and he'd get one of those electric wheelchairs...
拿着枪来到咱家门口
and he'd show up on our front lawn with a shotgun.
我们可以以牙还牙
Two can play at that game, Dad.
本，我们没有电动轮椅
Ben, we don't have an electric wheelchair.
但我们可以弄来机关枪
No, but we could get a machine gun...
像兰波一样干掉布克顿教练
and blow Mr. Brockton away, like in Rambo.
好吧，就算这样.
Okay, all right, all right. Let's say we do that.
咱胜利了!
All right, we won!
你以为胜利了.
You think you've won...
回到家，洗个澡.
and then you're back at home, and you're taking a shower...
准备上床睡觉，就在此时.
and you're getting ready for bed, and suddenly along comes...
布克顿太太来了
Mrs. Brockton.
冲进浴室？
Into our shower?
冲进客厅
No, into our living room...
她也有机枪
and she brings her own machine gun...
她干掉妈妈和凯罗
and she wipes out Mom and Carol.
那咱怎么办？
And then what do we do?
首先，我们得自己做饭吃了
Well, for one thing, we cook for ourselves and...
本，你怎么讨回公道？
Come on, Ben, don't you want to get even?
有了，把汽车卖了，买辆坦克
Yeah, we trade in the Volvo and get a tank.
对，好主意，咱跳上坦克
Yeah, that's good. Good, Ben, and then I hop into that tank...
把布克顿家夷为平地
and I motor over to the Brocktons, and I blow them all away.
棒极了!
All right!
且慢，他们家草坪上有地雷
But wait, Ben, they booby-trapped the front lawn.
那就太遗憾了
I'm sorry to hear that, Dad.
我们撤退时.
So just as I'm pulling away...
我和坦克都被炸飞了
that tank and your father get blown to Connecticut.
天哪
Oh, my gosh.
现在懂我意思了吗？
So you see what I'm getting at.
对，只剩下我和麦克了
Yeah, I've been left alone with Mike.
不，在你刷牙时.
No, because while you were brushing your teeth...
罗尼的表哥把麦克解决了
Rodney's cousins came and took care of Mike.
麦克也倒下了？剩下我一个？
They got Mike, too. So I'm all alone?
出人意料对吧？
Weird, isn't it?
几天前还有家庭，房子，汽车
Just a few days ago you had a family, a house, a Volvo.
现在只剩下淡淡的回忆.
Now all you've got left are your subscriptions to Boys' Life magazine...
还有前几天订的杂志
and a few faded memories.
值得吗？我们没有做胆小鬼
But, hey, it was worth it, wasn't it? 'Cause we didn't chicken out.
我们还手了
No, sir, we fought back.
还记得起因吗？
You remember how this got started again?
罗尼绊倒我了
Rodney tripped me.
是的，不过他已经死了
Yes, Rodney. Well, we won't have him to worry about anymore.
这问题也解决了
Guess we found a pretty good way to solve your problem.
不，这个解决办法不好
No, we didn't, Dad. It was a stupid way.
我还要喝一杯，你呢？
I need another drink. Want one?
好吧，倒
Sure, set 'em up.
你今天不是真的窝囊
So I guess you really didn't chicken out today, huh?
我没有窝囊
No, I didn't chicken out, Ben.
我只是认为暴力不能解决问题
I just feel that most of the time, fighting is not the answer...
所以有可能的话，尽量尝试别的办法
and that, whenever possible, we really must try to find a better way.
敬你这句话
I'll drink to that.
爸爸？
You know what, Dad?
什么事？
What, Ben?
你没被炸飞就太好了
I'm glad you didn't get blown to Connecticut.
我同意
So am I.
爷儿俩，怎样了？
How you doing, guys?
还好
Pretty good, Mom.
一定是珍妮了
Ah, that must be Jennifer.
可怜的女孩，还不知道 今晚麦克要对她的脚趾施暴
Poor girl, she has no idea what Mike's gonna do to her feet tonight.
珍妮，真漂亮
Jennifer, what a neat dress.
-进来吧 -谢谢
- Come on in. - Thanks.
天哪，露脚趾的鞋子!
Oh, my God. Open-toed shoes!
什么？
Pardon?
没什么
Never mind.
-珍妮，你真漂亮 -很漂亮
- Hi, Jennifer. Don't you look pretty. - Very nice.
来笑一笑
Let me take a picture.
珍妮
Jennifer.
麦克，真帅
Mike, you look so handsome.
就像酒家的服务员
Yeah, just like that waiter at the fish restaurant.
麦克，我有坏消息，婚礼取消了
Mike, I got terrible news. The wedding's off.
什么？
What?
我姐发现新郎和伴娘鬼混
My sister caught the groom in the confessional with her maid of honor.
她什么都说了
She broke the whole thing off.
我的功夫白费了？
After all I've been through?
她怎能这样对我？
How could she do this to me?
他确实多愁善感
We call him Mr. Sensitivity.
珍妮，我们要补救补救
Jennifer, we can't let this happen.
打个电话给你姐姐
I want you to go over here and call your sister right now...
好让她别断送美好的人生
and talk some sense into that girl before she throws her life away.
麦克，没用的，她们完了
Mike, it's no use. It's all over.
打个电话嘛
I'm just asking you to call her.
不行
I can't do that.
麦克
说不定可以嫁给别人呢
Hey, maybe she could marry somebody else.
好吧，过来
Mike!
什么？
Okay, okay, fine. Okay, come here.
过来吧
What?
Just come here.
我实在没心思跳舞
Mike, I'm really not in the mood for this.
请把电话给我
Somebody give me the phone.
麦姬，咱家出了个小魔王了
Maggie, I think we might have created a monster.
本，球打得很好
You're looking good out there, Ben.
布克顿教练离职后，我获得了重生
I feel like a new man since Coach Brockton got the boot.
新教练来了，他跟球迷聊了很久了
Uh-oh, here comes the coach. It's five laps for talking with the fans.
看我的!
Show off!
好吧，大家过来
All right, come on, you guys. Let's get together here.
明天第一场比赛!
First game's tomorrow. Let's go.
打球应该怎样？
-我们该怎样？ -努力训练!
- What are we gonna do? - Try hard!
要有体育精神!
And how are we gonna play?
-若是输了呢？ -你会杀死我们!
In a sportsmanlike manner!
是吗？
- And what if we don't win? - You'll kill us!
说笑的!
How do I mean that?
Facetiously!
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01